How big does AI have to get to justify
the trillions in infrastructure
spending? Let's talk about it with the
leading authorities from semi analysis
right [music] after this. Welcome to Big
Technology Podcast, a show for
coolheaded and nuanced conversation of
the tech world and beyond. The AI
infrastructure numbers just seem to be
getting bigger with no end in sight. So,
we're going to talk about what the
physics of this entire buildout looks
like and whether it can continue to
sustain itself without not maybe not
destroying the world, but destroying the
economy. Uh, cuz we have some very
interesting guests to speak with us
about it. Today, we're joined today by
Dylan Patel, the CEO and founder of Semi
analysis, [music] and Jordan Anos,
member of the technical staff at Semi
analysis to talk all about everything uh
going on within [music] the
infrastructure buildout. Uh Dylan
Jordan, welcome to the show.
>> Thanks. Great to be here.
>> Let's just start by talking about the
scale of what we're seeing uh in this AI
infrastructure buildout if we can. Uh
Dylan, there's like a chart going around
X right now that compares uh the AI
infrastructure buildout to previous
buildouts in the past like railroads,
um like highways. And the chart is
showing that the percent of GDP for the
AI buildout today is about 3.6% 6% or
sorry the P the median is about 3.6%
uh the average year compared to 2.2% 2%
for the railroads. And basically the
commentary is that this is far bigger,
right? That would put it basically 50%
bigger than railroads even in terms of
its share of GDP. And the commentary is
this is bigger than anything we've ever
seen before on a scale that is, you
know, effectively unprecedented. Um I'd
love to hear your perspective on just
how big this is, whether that's the
right way to look at it. Um and then
what it means if we're building out
something this big.
>> Yeah, I mean uh the first thing I when
that chart was going around, I was like,
well, people's numbers are too low. It's
actually much higher than that already.
Um,
>> really? Okay. So, share the real
numbers.
>> Yeah. Yeah. So, so like I mean it's it's
if you look at like next year um capex
across the US will be on the order of $2
trillion uh include not just data
centers and chips but also all the rest
of the supply chain that people are
investing in. Um so you're close to $2
trillion of capex. Um and then you stack
on top of that uh GDP is like close to
30 30 and some change trillion. So
you're at like you know five or 6% right
not not 3% or 2%. Um so so sort of my
thought process is actually like oh wow
these numbers are lower than the actual
because people are understating the
amount and size of capex that's
happening in the US and and and North
America and the world. Um, and I think
like part of this is because, you know,
with railroads, your capex is in the
country that you're deploying it in.
With fiber, your capex is in the country
you're deploying it in. But for AI
infrastructure, your capex in America is
actually a lot of it's being used to
serve outside of America uses, right?
So, if you look at, for example, Europe,
most of Europe's inference for anthropic
is in America and most of OpenAI's
inference in Europe is in America. Um
and and similarly if you look at a lot
of Asian countries um and so there is a
bit of this like this this you know
capex in America is actually like much
higher as a result um because one you're
doing all the training here and then two
you're actually serving other countries
from data centers in America um and so
ultimately you're sort of at this stage
where capacity is much um the economic
impact of it is much larger um than any
other sort of physical infrastructure.
investment cycle ever before.
>> All right, Jordan. And you are the
author of Clustermax 3.0. This is semi
analysis rankings of the GPU uh cloud
systems. Uh basically putting a lot of
the hyperscalers and the neoclouds uh in
tiers talking a little bit about their
performance and we're going to get to
that in a bit. But I I you know you do
look across the board in your report and
this is something that I I'd like you to
comment on. Uh basically we're looking
at um where the uh the hyperscaler
quarterly yearon-year capex growth is
going and in the third quarter of 2026
uh the growth is at 116%.
Year-over-year which is astonishing. um
the consensus estimates so what Wall
Street is expecting to come after that
you know they they drop down in the
first quarter well in the fourth quarter
to below 100% year-over-year growth and
then the first quarter next year uh in
the 70% and it continues to drop from
there and I think this is a cycle that
we're used to right where it's like well
you know we're we're on a bigger base so
it can't possibly exceed expectations
again and it can't possibly double again
um so I'm curious to hear from your
perspective in your research, uh, do you
think that we're actually going to see
that trend like the growth is going to
decelerate or are, you know, are we
again falling into this trap or is Wall
Street again falling into this trap
where it's like, all right, you've
you're basically at the biggest numbers
you could possibly imagine, but you
still need to think bigger. [sighs]
Yeah, I think we're definitely going to
hit limits towards the end of next year
and into
>> Wait, Jordan, before you answer
seriously, I got I gota I got, you know,
it's like when you ask a kid what's the
biggest number they can think of and
they say like,00
[laughter]
right and and now and it's like no no no
we're at a trillion babe.
>> Yeah. [laughter]
>> Yeah. Four commas club. Um
>> so wait in in Dylan in in this example
the kid is Wall Street. [laughter]
Not not making any any statements that
people are children. Just uh yeah, go
ahead. Sorry. [laughter]
>> Dylan may have an a habit of referring
to his employees and his customers as
kids sometimes, but that aside, um
[laughter]
>> I think I think I use a much more mean
word.
>> Okay. Yeah,
>> I like where this is going already.
>> We're we're running out of big numbers.
There are there are things to uh look at
when it comes to the buildout. This
could be everything from like industrial
equipment to firms that are prepared to
do EPC work like engineering,
procurement, construction to chips to
cooling systems to you know all the
components that go outside of that and
um an IT you know estate basically. Uh
there's a lot of work being done to
expand this supply chain in order to be
able to accommodate for all of this
capex to to go into it. Um, and it's a
lot of it's working and so we're going
to see massive growth, but yeah, you you
can't just have tripledigit growth and
accelerate the second derivative, you
know, even further from where it is
right now. Um, you run out of things and
I think the biggest thing right now is
uh twofold. One is like it it becomes
really hard for the biggest NeoClouds in
hyperscalers to just organize and
marshall the resources required to build
another gigawatt on top of what they're
already trying to build, for example.
and it becomes pretty hard for them to
raise the capital. Even though there's
incredible returns on a lot of these
investments already, you still just need
to find the capital to pour into these
projects and that's uh you know a
difficult thing to do when you're when
we're talking about numbers in the
trillions of dollars.
>> I would I would say the other thing is
like by definition the numbers have to
shrink. Um you know this year we have
10x growth entropic going from sub10
billion of revenue to north of 10 uh
north of 100 billion. So, they had 10x
growth. Um, definitionally, they're just
not going to have a trillion dollars of
revenue by the end of next year. Um, so
yes, there's some decelerating growth
there. Um, you know, Nvidia's revenue,
uh, growth is still 2x year, but it's,
you know, it's not as much as it was at
an earlier point. Um, just because it is
definitionally harder to grow 2x off the
same base. So, 3x off the same base. So,
it's sort of like, um, same applies to
like other firms. So it's it is it is
definitionally like definitely
decelerating.
>> Okay. So the growth on spending is going
to need to decelerate at some point. But
the growth on revenue and profit for
that matter is going to have to
accelerate you know beyond uh it's
basically going to have to trail this
big infrastructure uh buildout and
accelerate probably beyond where we've
seen uh the the dollars being spent. I
mean you would you would imagine uh to
facilitate all the AI action. And
there's been uh further further
conversations that have circulated about
this. And Dylan, let me just throw these
numbers out to you. Right. So this is a
Goldman Sachs uh report. Um and sorry,
so Goldman Sachs, they say Meta, this is
a a tweet, right? Meta's committed
corporate suicide after taking on
insurmountable debt that the company
will struggle to pay back. There's Bane.
Bane says hyperscalers will need 6
trillion in revenue, not ever. This is
per year by 2020 by 2031 uh to break
even. And there's a Colombia professor
uh Stinvan Newberg who said that America
will need to spend roughly 3.5 trillion
annually on AI services by 2032 8.8% of
GDP to justify today's massive data
center investment. Um what do you think
of these these sort of assessments of
where the spending and where the revenue
needs to be to pay off the investments
and do they have a chance at making good
on those investments?
>> Yes. I mean I think I think everyone's
numbers for revenue requirements are
quite low um given the pace of where
this buildout is going to go. I think I
think it's going to go like I think
revenue will be much higher than that uh
by 2031 for example. Um I mean there's a
couple points here right? One is like
you know how much is people are people
spending on capex and then revenue and
the revenue always trails the capex.
These infrastructure investments are six
years on an accounting basis at least
depreciable assets although there's
quite a bit of evidence that they're
actually going to last longer than that
but you know six years is let's just
continue to use six years. So if I spend
a trillion dollars today on you know AI
data center and GPUs um the GPUs are
lasting six years the data centers are
lasting 15. Um but that means
definitionally in terms of revenue um
either I could assume it's a straight
line right so then over the 6 years I
need to call it 1.5 trillion of revenue
so $250 billion of revenue a year for
that trillion dollars of capex or it's
going to be something sloped where the
first year is much less and the last
year is much higher um to get the
payback um as far as like you know like
statements on meta it's like this is
this is just kind of silly because meta
meta at any point can just stop buying
new stuff and their cash flow can easily
pay for all the stuff that they've
signed, right? They just don't have to,
you know, they don't have to build a
hundred billion dollars of data centers
next year. They could pull the plug
whenever they feel like it. Um there's
obviously contracts that they've
committed to, but there's also a lot of
stuff they haven't committed to yet. Um
and so as far as like the solveny of
Meta, like they're completely solvent.
They're completely fine. Um and then the
question is like what revenue do they
make on top of that? Um and as far as
like AI's impact in the in the US
economy, um yeah, I mean if if AI
revenue is only $3 trillion in 2031,
then yeah, we'll have big problems. Um
but you know, I I'm I'm like of the
belief that we can get to like 600 700
million across openthropic alone by the
by December of next year. Um I'm of the
opinion that you can uh get to, you
know, 1 and a.5 trillion maybe even by
2020 end of 2027 uh with just those two
companies. Um so that's end of 27. So
then the payback is clear, right? Um you
know where they're getting that from. Um
ultimately um the the capacity that
people are building out is matched to
what they think business is coming to.
Um, and so there's always going to be a
mismatch if we're in the building phase
of how much infrastructure are you
spending on versus what's the AI revenue
because that AI revenue for today is
really based on the infrastructure you
spent in prior years. Um, and right now
capex is not going up at 10x a year but
inference just revenue just went up 10x
year on year um for the AI labs. And so
um we've seen entropic is now you know
profitable in terms of um compute cost
minus revenue or revenue minus compute
cost. um both training and inference
combined um and OpenAI gets there you
know within the next couple quarters uh
maybe two or three quarters um so based
on at least what like we expect in the
tokconomics model so so I think you know
those companies are already uh breaking
even if you look at like Amazon for
example the biggest builder of AI
infrastructure they all of their AI
infrastructure investments are
profitable today um now you know the
customers that for them could go
insolvent those customers being
openthropic etc Um but right now they
are solvent on those um you know making
very strong gross margins. In fact AI
has made their gross margin go up in the
most recent quarter um from bedrock and
AI revenue from Bedrock. Um so so yes AI
revenue needs to grow a lot. Um, but I
would posit that like being able to
automate all the stuff that we've been
able to and being able to build all the
stuff that the world has been able to um
is going to generate meaningful revenue
and surplus for the consumer ultimately.
>> Yeah, I think we need to stretch it a
little bit in our minds to understand
what we are going to measure as AI
revenue going into the future. If these
companies really do have the best models
in the world that are capable of
effectively all knowledge work, you can
imagine them going into a whole bunch of
different industries beyond coding and
having returns on their investments
similar to what they've seen in coding.
So you can look at things like robotics
and self-driving vehicles. You can look
at drug discovery. You can look at just
health and life sciences generally. And
we can take this across all these
industries and say if they want to bring
a product to market like a cancer drug
or like a self-driving vehicle, you can
just imagine how much revenue they can
potentially return based on the
investments they have today. And if they
have the AI, the system to be able to
produce the knowledge work required to
build that product incredibly well, I
think they're the only ones that can
really compete on the frontier of being
able to do these things. And so I think
people lack the creativity to understand
how returns can be viewed beyond the
like claude code subscription and per
token pricing regime of today.
>> Yeah, there's there's this chart that
looks at how much we're spending as a
share of GDP. This is just 2025. So a
share of GDP health is 18% that's the
top category. Food is 9.1%.
AI services is 8.8%. It's the third
category in 2025. I imagine it's going
to lap or it will pass food in 2026. So
guys, I I'm just curious where's this
money coming from? Like it, you know,
let's say OpenAI and Anthropic combined
get to $700 billion in revenue next
year. Um, is the money coming from these
companies labor pools? Is it just
additive because they can sell more? Uh,
where is the money that these companies
are the customers of these companies? uh
where's that money coming from that they
can funnel it into the AI companies?
>> It it's a few factors, right? First off
is um obviously companies are going to
be able to accelerate what they're
building um and so they can invest more.
Um increasing share of R&D dollars will
go towards AI. Increasing share of cost
of goods sold dollars will go towards
AI. Um but also you'll have a
significant amount of money sort of
going coming from um you know labor as
well, right? labor and I don't think
labor shrinks per se. I think the rest
of the economy grows so fast, at least
in the short term, that labor labor sort
of stays, you know, flattish. Um and and
so like um you know, in the past, we've
had different cycles across the economy,
but one long-standing one has been labor
share of GDP has fallen over the
decades, and it's been a steady slow
since the 70s. And so a lot of the like
strife that people say, "Oh, America's
economy sucks." And yet, oh look, the
economy is bigger is actually well like
labor share of economy is shrank and
that's why um in reality a lot more of
the labor the value is getting acrewing
to capital. What AI does is it's going
to supercharge that trend, long-term
trend of labor share versus capital
share because AI tokens are gener
basically just capital um you know in
the form of chips and data centers that
are sitting there and creating labor um
and so that labor share is going to fall
even faster um and and and so you know I
I I would hope and and for society that
that that's my belief you know and maybe
it's like a irrational belief but I
believe that we will just grow the
economy so fast that labor
in terms of dollars will not shrink. Um,
and it might even grow slowly. It's just
that the rest of the economy grows so
fast. Um, and that's where that's sort
of where it comes from, right? So, all
these companies that do uh offer various
services, their services are going to
get better. They're going to be able to
charge more. They're going to be able to
sell more. Um, and they're going to be
able to do it with fewer people. Um, or
another way to look at it is they're
going to have the same number of people
and their business just going to get
better. Um and that's that's and and and
there's a number of industries where
this is possible, right? Um
you know, obviously coding is an area
where people have done it quite a bit.
Um obviously general white collar work
is getting rapidly automated, but also
companies are just able to do a shitload
more than they were able to do in the
past. Um but there's a lot of industries
like pharma and uh trading um and chip
design and such, right? Like chip design
is a great example, right? chips. The
number of American R&D engineers working
in chip design has been basically flat
for 20 years. And yet the economy for it
has exploded. Now, obviously
manufacturing isn't, we're not counting
manufacturing. We're just counting the
designers. Um, but the designers are
like, you know, two of the most valuable
companies in the world, right? Nvidia,
Broadcom, um, as well as like Google and
all these other companies that are
making their own chips and many others,
right? These designers have not really
grown that much in terms of number of
people. It's been flat as an industry
for us and yet the value that's accured
has exploded. And why is that? There
have been a lot of tools. Now what is
what does AI assisted chip design now
do? Well, now all of the chips that are
across the economy get better and
better. Your phones are going to get
better. Your you know AirPods are going
to get better, the chips in them. Chips
for robots are going to get better.
Chips for obviously AI um are going to
get better. Chips for all sorts of
things. Bluetooth and GPS and all these
other things. Sensors um for gas leaks
or whatever that Bosch makes. these are
all just going to get better because AI
can help you design chips. You do the
same number of people, revenue grows,
margins grow, um everything looks
fantastic, right? And that's sort of
like there's many industries where this
can get replicated. Um in my view,
>> Dylan, you've said that uh I think in
the past you've said something to the
extent of knowledge work is effed. So do
you no longer believe that? Um
I think most knowledge work okay like
let's separate like my belief in like
Looney Tunes 2035 versus like [laughter]
you know 2028
um I think in 20 I think for the next
you know X number of years as long as AI
is very powerful but it is not better
than humans in most every way the most
the most high agency people are going to
be able to do the coolest stuff they're
going to be able to make way bigger
impacts on the world Um now you know in
like the case where AI is just better
than everyone um that that could change
drastically right um you know then then
like knowledge work is screwed and
actually like you know what matters is
like people being able to like play
games and have fun people being able to
act people being able to like you know
do the things that humans do that humans
only appreciate in each other if the AI
doesn't kill us all right but that's
sort of like you know [snorts]
>> we we won't go there today. Um Jordan,
you know, this is kind of in your your
area of expertise. I want to get started
talking a little bit about the risks to
like what might derail this story. Um
and you know, we'd already talked about
the fact that uh there are some
contracts that a company like Meta uh
could, you know, may not have to go
through with. Um you're obviously
looking a lot at the businesses of the
Neoclouds which are dependent on uh
companies like Meta actually making good
uh on the on the promises that they've
they've put forth to build with these
companies. Um is this sort of an
underappreciated risk that like
everything looks like [snorts] fairly
fine right now if you speak to one of
these Neoclouds because they'll tell you
that they have the best customers in the
world. uh they have the Metas and Meta
will make good on the on the um on the
promise and they're raising debt based
off of this. Uh but in reality the risk
might be that a company like Meta might
just decide yeah we're not going to do
that and that the contracts might not be
as binding as uh you know the Neoclouds
tell us they are.
>> Okay. So I I want to be clear about one
thing Dylan was talking about there in
terms of termination versus what's going
on with meta and the neoclouds which is
that generally speaking these
hyperscalers
or you know large frontier labs who are
signing up with contracts for the
Neoclouds do not have arbitrary
cancellation rights on like a monthly
basis where they can just pull the plug
and the contract's done. Uh generally
speaking, they're signing five years,
six-year term lengths and they're off
taking the full capacity and they have a
set, you know, hourly rate and total
contract value that's very very
attractive to the NeoCloud providers
because those guys have gone out and
secured land and power and built a site
and even in some cases purchased the
chips respectively before they've
actually gone and done that contract.
what Dylan's referring to with the the
potential to slow down or pause or
cancel projects, it's more with respect
to the self-build sites, which is to say
like Meta has massive campuses that are
going to serve as more of a base load of
capacity going into the future, which
they can either choose to buy chips for
or just leave as an empty shell for
years if they want to slow down and not
go as hard as they can. And generally
speaking, construction costs while very
expensive are a small percentage of the
total cost of a new chip uh project.
Like in other words, the concrete and
the steel and the walls is quite you
know it's important and big and and you
know very a real challenge to get it
done but on a dollar basis like the HBM
and the optics and the GPUs themselves
are the the bigger uh portion of the
bill. Um, and so you know what it's what
it's looking like right now is that all
of these big companies are really
needing to contend with the massive
growth that they're expected to pursue
by their demand from their customer
base. either that's meta or openai or
enthropic who have demand on their
consumerf facing applications like uh
chat gpt or cloud code or uh codeex or
uh even muse from meta things like that
in order to serve that demand they need
GPUs and it's profitable s to serve the
demand so they need to ramp up and be
prepared to roll this thing out to the
billions of monthly active users on the
meta uh different you know uh surfaces
that they serve and approaching a
billion of monthly active users for
chatpt and hundreds of millions for uh
cloud code and things like that. So
anyway, um with that distinction in
mind, what's the the risk with project
cancellation or or a downturn or things
like that? I mean, in order to for for
us to um forecast some sort of change in
the demand supply curve there, you'd
really need to see demand slow. Um,
there are hard constraints on how many
chips you can produce, how many data
centers you can build, and how fast this
stuff is going to come online. And as of
right now, all of the modeling we can do
basically shows that demand outstrips
supply. And so, is demand 10% more than
supply right now? Is it 50%, is it
infinite? I mean, we we don't get to
answer that question because we are not
able to catch up to demand with the
supply of GPUs that you can bring online
right now. And so when that question
gets answered, if it gets answered, if
we find limits to the demand for
knowledge work, to the demand for
intelligence from the economy, then
we'll we'll be able to figure out who
needs to slow at what time, where, and
how that plays out
yet. But so far, I guess those limits
haven't been found. So, um, all right.
Uh, before we get into Cluster Max, one
last topic I want to cover, uh, big IPO
on it way, uh, which is, of course, the
anthropic IPO. Uh Dylan, you had a very
interesting tweet about it. I'm just
gonna read it. You said, "You can't
invest in the anthropic IPO at$ two
trillion dollars because it could be
zero and I'm or it could be 20
trillion, but at 20 trillion, we're all
fucked." Uh can you explain that and and
tell us a little bit about what you mean
by that?
>> Um to be clear, it's it's entirely a
post. Um I was I was like
>> You know what? I I get it, but I think
there's some truth to to what you're
saying. So talk to us about it. I I'm
I'm generally extremely bullish
Anthropic. I think Anthropic will make
you make, you know, be a very successful
company in the world. Anthropic could
even be the first company to be a 10
trillion valuation company in the world.
Like I'm like that bullish
entropic. But at the same time, um for
them to be a 10 or 20 trillion valuation
company, especially 20, um they're first
of all, their multiples on revenue are
going to have to collapse quite a bit.
Um, you know, so they used to, you know,
they used to raise at 30x and now
they're, you know, IPO is going to be,
you know, let's call it they're at
hundred billion dollars of revenue and
they're going to maybe be at 20x. Um,
you know, if they get to 10 trillion, I
bet you they would need to be at like a
trillion dollars of revenue um or
something crazy, right, like that,
right? Um, which could happen at some
point in 28 um or 29. um you know it
depends of course like the stock market
can also go crazy and like make
multiples go crazy but you know in the
world where they're doing you know where
they're worth 20 trillion you know I
don't think their revenue I don't think
they're even at a 10x sales multiple now
they're probably at like a 5x or even
less um in which case they're you know
if they're at $20 trillion of revenue
they're at are they at like 2 3 4
trillion $20 trillion valuation 2 three
4 trillion revenue and at that point you
know what is the state of AI if on
[snorts] a 150 $50 billion global
economy or trillion dollar economy,
they're generating multiple trillion
dollars of revenue and by far the
largest company in the world. Like AI's
capabilities are freaking insane. Um, in
which case like you know all of this
worry of like whether it's AI kill us
all or AI so good that everyone loses
their jobs and because distribution of
that earnings is going to be heavily
leveraged to the people who own
anthropic stock or um constituent supply
chains of it and not distributed well
then people are going to have dist dis
distress and like overthrow governments
because all of the growth is
accumulating to a very small number of
people. So like these things could like
tear the fabric of society apart and
therefore like if you believe anthropic
will get to 20 trillion, you know,
society as a whole could be
>> Jordan, do you have similar worries?
>> I think Yeah, I think I think uh there's
a lot to do to get to that point. Like
um I I actually don't think I'm
necessarily as worried uh as Dylan.
>> I'm optimistic, by the way. I just
painted the pessimistic picture. I'll go
optimistic.
>> Yeah. I mean like the the rosy
optimistic view is kind of what I
described earlier which is like if
they're getting to $20 trillion of
revenue. This is not done on a per token
metered basis for people using cla code
as a product and I don't think you know
you go and see cloud code go 20x better
from where it is right now in terms of
like quality and that drives the
revenue. I think that they get into
other areas of business and I think I
would trust Anthropic quite a bit to
bring like I said earlier a cancer drug
to market or something like that and
we've seen similar stuff happen recently
with GLP1s just be such a meaningful
thing for so many people in the economy
and as a result you know companies like
Lily have have had massive uh you know
returns on on that incredible research
that led to those uh incredible drugs
that help people and so I think um I
would be more optimistic for the future
where [laughter] theoretically
anthropics at a $20 trillion valuation.
Um, but I do think that there are a lot
of uh going to be a lot of bumps along
the road along the way. Um, which is to
say
going back to your to your question
previously, like how can they possibly
serve all of this demand and train these
models and uh, you know, have
intelligence diffused to all of these
different parts of the economy so that
people can realize the benefits. And I
think the way you do that is to build
compute and it so depends on you know
the nitty-gritty details of construction
and installing GPUs and running them
reliably and all of that. Like to me the
center of the world is the NeoClouds on
that road from a $2 trillion IPO to a
2020 20 trillion valuation in the public
markets.
Yeah, anthropic uh kind of an
interesting business case, right?
They're spending all this money on
infrastructure. Uh even in the S1, you
saw big losses accompanying their
revenue. Although um Dylan, as you
mentioned, it looks like what they've
done is they've turned the tide a bit
and they're making more money uh right
now than they're spending on compute. Um
talk a little bit because I think the
the um the belief here is that a company
like Anthropic is a low margin business
or at least much less than uh than
software. But that doesn't actually seem
to be the case. And you guys have run
the numbers. I would say like if you
look at like Salesforce which is
probably like one of the greatest SAS
companies out there um you know I mean I
think like at least like consistently
grown to become one of the biggest SAS
companies um their gross margins are
like 75%. and Enthropic on their
inference is doing 75% gross margins a
little bit higher even um you know
especially on the frontier models so
it's sort of like well and it took it
took Salesforce quite some time to get
there right they were not at 75% when
they IPOed um you know they they took
quite a bit of time actually they were
but then they like you know the mid in
the late 2000s like they were you know I
think like it took they were like not
quite there it took you know anthropic
quite a bit less time to get to that
strong levels of growth margin. Um, and
if you look at many other SAS companies,
they're not even that high. Um, and then
the other thing is like their customer
acquisition cost is insane, right? If
you look at like a a SAS company, it's
like, you know, fine, my uh my COGS is
really low, but then my customer
acquisition cost can be as high as like
30%. Um, and Anthropic has near no
customer acquisition cost. Right now,
obviously, they have a humongous R&D
spend. um but their R&D spend has grown
slower than their revenue. Um and so now
they've reached profitability and
there's no reason why that trend doesn't
continue, right? And they continue to
grow more profitable. Um so at least uh
operating margin wise and then and then
like scalability is the other thing,
right? Like the the beautiful thing
about a lot of SAS companies even if
your customer acquisition cost is so
high, you know, as long as your margins
are high enough to pay for it initially,
eventually you don't have to reacquire
that customer. Now you've got this super
profitable business. But with like the
AI labs, their business seems somewhat
sticky. Yes, there's all this like
messaging of like, oh, you know, Meta's
cutting spend or Microsoft cutting spend
or what have you, but ultimately the
revenue has only been a straight line up
on the chart and almost every customer's
only grown on revenue for them. And uh
switching cost even when you know some
other Chinese model comes out or comes
out with a better model doesn't really
shift the spend share that much. um for
existing customers um you end up with
like this like pretty sticky customer
potentially who is growing revenue at
some pace and there's no customer
acquisition cost and the margins are
high so it's arguably a better business
than software is is an AI lab
>> if you can successfully
>> but how much is the risk the fact that
like there this pacing the frontier um
mo movement movement is coming out um
>> I think that's just signaling I think
it's completely
>> talk about that you don't think that's
going to that's true at all.
>> Um, I think pacing the frontier is a
responsible thing to do if you believe
that we could kill ourselves.
Um, I don't necessarily think that
um they will pace the frontier too much
though. I think like there's there's
like very little pacing they can do
given the race that they're in. Um, and
people have made skits about this, but
like you know, you know, Daario can't
slow down because he doesn't trust Sam
and Sam's not gonna slow down and Sam
can't slow down much because same with
Daario. Obviously, they're going to slow
down a little bit when they have these
massive security in incidents. Um, and
neither of them can slow down because
China's not too far behind. So, it's
like sort of like very difficult.
>> That's reassuring. [laughter]
All right. Um, look, we're going to take
a quick break and then when we come
back, we're going to talk a little bit
about, um, the state of the AI clouds,
uh, cluster max, of course, uh, and then
we'll continue on with some more
questions about the technology and the
business. So, we'll do that when we're
back right after this. And we're back
here on Big Technology podcast with
Dylan Patel and Jordan Anos from Semi
analysis. Semi analysis, I'm sure you're
familiar. It's the Bible for anything AI
infrastructure. Uh, these guys are the
best. very grateful to have your time
both of you and um you know definitely
recommend you at least uh check out the
blog. You can also get semi analysis on
subscanalysis.com.
It's the number one technology
newsletter uh and welld deserved. So
congratulations guys.
>> In the newsletter you can uh find the
clustermax 3.0. Uh it's it's actually
even if you're not technical I was
talking with Jordan about this. It's a
fun read. It goes into the state of the
buildout. Um, and the subhead tells you,
you know, it's already kicked off in the
right way in the gory detail, the
reliability, performance, support, and
pricing and security of the GPU cloud
providers. There's a lot in there. Um,
there's a lot of areas we can go in this
uh Jordan and Dylan, but let's begin
with the role of Nvidia here. Um the
report you know though it spends most of
the time on the technical side of things
does go into the fact that uh Nvidia is
playing a ma major role in keeping these
clustries
providing uh infrastructure AI
infrastructure maybe to some of the
frontier labs but really across the
board uh and making this whole thing
work and Nvidia has been backstopping uh
a lot of their um their businesses with
uh as you write um revenue floors
landlord guarantees and leases that it
plans to transfer to third parties
helping the Neo Labs and AI labs in
obtaining investment grade financing
without a hyperscaler being involved. Um
Jordan to you on this one. Uh you know
there's the the criticism sort of like
the Edotron criticism of this uh of this
industry is that Nvidia is basically
funding uh the demand for all these
Neoclouds and without that uh backs stop
um you know this whole thing would
basically evaporate and make Nvidia look
a bit smaller and make these neoclouds
um you know non nonviable. What's your
thought on that after going so deep into
this?
>> Uh yeah, well I mean both in Clustermax
and in another article we did recently
called Nvidia's backs stop universe, we
go into a little bit of the dynamics of
what backs stops are and how they help
the Neoclouds raise the money they need
to deploy the GPUs which then customers
are renting pretty strongly at this
point. And uh the number that we have is
that currently we've got tracking of
$588 billion of offbalance sheet backs
stops that Nvidia is supporting right
now, which is one of yet another
unbelievable number in the list that
we've been going through on this podcast
so far. Um I mean, but Nvidia's revenue
is approaching 400 about to cross 500
billion. So we're talking about really
big numbers there. For context, that's
like 2.5% of the M2 money supply in the
US. So obviously there's massive massive
amounts of money going on uh in this um
universe as we refer to it and uh I mean
the only thing I can say about this is
that it just seems really pragmatic from
Nvidia. They really uh want a wide
diversity of customers. They want don't
want to be dependent on the hyperscalers
for all of their revenue. Um they also
don't want their customers to be
dependent on getting their chips from a
select set of three or four different
hyperscalers. And so they have every
incentive to have a a nice healthy
market with a diversity of options and
uh lots of selection for all of the
customers to go uh work with. And in
order to deliver on that, people have
more problems than just uh raising the
money required to buy the GPUs. Well,
first of all, they need the guarantee
that if they raise the money, those
creditors are going to see returns. And
that requires you know some sort of
investment grade offtaker which Nvidia
can serve in these cases in many in many
of these cases. But the way it's worked
so far is that Nvidia signs up as that
offtaker and then when it comes time to
actually you know take those GPUs for
themselves for their own internal
research work. Somebody else comes along
and wants them more at a higher price.
And so then they sell them to their to
those guys. They don't take them for
their internal research and they roll on
to the next one. And for everybody who
says that Nvidia, you know, is doing
this for some nefarious purpose or to to
keep some bubble going, I'd encourage
you to look at the quality of Nvidia's
research. They publish more models on
Hugging Face than anybody else. They
have incredible CI across the suite of
software that they they support on their
GPUs and they train models like Neotron.
We're not the biggest fan of these
models or this software. you know we
think there should be a diverse
ecosystem but the idea that Nvidia does
not use their own GPUs for research that
serves the purposes of their company is
you know itself wrong and then the
dynamic that we've seen is that this
amount of compute is actually not a
meaningful portion of Nvidia's revenue
it's it's a very small percentage of
Nvidia's total revenue that is you know
going back for their own internal
research workloads so what we're seeing
is just that they are supporting
Neocloud's build out the capacity for
the demand from the customers which is
so incredibly strong right now and hard
to serve. Um, and then maybe the the
last thing to say about this is that
it's not just the chips. Like we we we
track a whole wide range of things that
they're backstopping. This is everything
from like, you know, the construction
costs, the memory suppliers, the people
building fabs, the people building
industrial equipment. I mean, it's not
just like I need help raising money for
my GPUs. is I need help raising money
for all of the other things in the
supply chain which is just the long pole
in the tent for that specific project.
>> Yep. Let's talk about security because
um you know the first image in this
report uh is a quote tweet of an Ilia
subsever post which was made right after
uh the hugging face incident. Uh Ilia
says neoclouds have limited cyber
security. Next time agents successfully
go rogue, uh they'll try taking over a
Neocloud to run more copies. This is
bad. Thus, Neocloud should greatly
strengthen their cyber security and
every company with strong cyber models
uh should help with that. This is a rare
tweet uh from Ilia. Dylan, what do you
make of this? Uh is this sounds to me
like if he's out saying this right,
remember he's building this stuff
himself. Uh I'd say super intelligence
that we might have a problem here. Yeah.
So, we we posted an article titled most
Neoclouds suck at security. Um
documenting,
>> by the way, the art for that uh is is
incredible. We'll put it on the screen
uh for those who are watching
this guy getting [laughter]
>> Yeah, exactly. getting stabbed by
everybody and it's like it's SOC2
compliant. [laughter]
>> Um but yeah, so we we posted that report
and then uh that you know like maybe
eight or eight hours later or whatever,
Ilia uh posted his tweet.
um because they are very much um you
[snorts] know using various clouds um
they're obviously super secretive um and
care a lot about the secrecy of like
what they're working on but also they
are big believers in super intelligence
um you know I guess safe super
intelligence SSI they were the first you
know Trump actually copied Ilia Ilia's
first with another one right um first to
reasoning first to uh LLM scaling and
now first to uh super intelligence
branding. Um, but Ilia sort of tweeted
that out. Um, and and it sort of echoed
what we wrote, right? Which is like,
look, most of these clouds are terrible
at security. You can get open- source
models to just hack Neoclouds or get
access to stuff within other within
Neoclouds. Um, you know, GLM 5.3
especially is like really good at this.
So, open source Chinese models can just
hack dozens of the Neoclouds that exist
out there and you can go look at what
other people are doing. And so we've
seen stuff like this um at other clouds.
There was a cloud that you know we we
didn't even intend to, but we just
accidentally ended up like seeing all of
the other clients on that cluster,
seeing what stuff they had in storage,
see what stuff they had in slurm, etc.
And there were like intelligence
agencies, right? Like on this. So we
immediately
like reported it to them. We're like,
yo,
>> which intelligence agencies?
>> We we cannot say I don't think that's a
valid thing to say.
national like like federal well security
agencies governments
>> they were not American
>> they were not American but we said it
was for a country that was in a has a
top 10 GDP it's not like some tiny
country
>> I'm I'm losing my mind here that that
was possible
>> yeah and it's like it's like if we were
malicious and by the way there were
probably a dozen other customers and
maybe one of them was malicious we could
have just like seen what they were
training right and they were training
models and running models for their
themselves presumably
um because this was a GPU
infrastructure. So what else would you
do with a bunch of Blackwell GPUs?
>> Yeah, we we throw around this this word
sovereign AI and it it gets entangled
with the concept of a neocloud many
times and and people even when they're
raising money, they use this word a lot
because they view compute as
infrastructure. And I think that's
exactly right. This is just like the
telecommunications buildout where this
is this infrastructure is viewed by the
sovereign nations that are deploying it
and are involved in this as a asset that
the country would like to control and
have sovereignty over and they believe
that similar to what you're saying at
the beginning of the show uh they want
to be a net token importer or exporter
and that is driven by the infrastructure
they build which means data centers with
GPUs inside of it and so I think it's
actually no surprise that uh federal
government research and intelligence
agencies are on some of these clusters
sharing
infrastructure with others. You would
like them to have an air gap data
center, but if there's exactly one
facility in the entire country with
GB300, NVL72,
I mean, it's a sellers market.
>> Goodness. Uh all right. Well, there goes
my sleep tonight. So um let's let you
know you you you do in this report also
rank uh you know a lot of these
hyperscalers um into tiers and and the
neoclouds into tiers and the at the top
tier is coreweave and nebus um I'm more
interested in the second tier and that
is Oracle and Google cloud um mostly
Jordan because you know I I you know I
have like in the document that I put
together for you know our conversation
today I have like a lot of like topics
and sentences um that I've like pulled
out of the report with questions and
then with Oracle, I just have Oracle and
then a bunch of question marks because
that's kind of how I feel about that
company. I don't know how to feel about
about them there. Obviously, their debt
has been rated um you know, not well by
the rating agencies. They're making this
all in bet. Um they rate pretty high and
they actually in your report have been
credited with pioneering some
techniques. Um, but I would love to get
your readout on on Oracle and you know
whether whether this has been a smart
bet for them and whether you know
they're they're going to to rise in
glory or or sort of fall in flames like
a lot of people anticipate. I think the
key thing about cluster max is it is not
stock recommendations, right? Um it is
not anything to do with hey this Neil
cloud is going to build a gigawatt next
year or 200 megawws u which is far more
relevant for the stock than you know
what how good are they at operating a
cluster right um has nothing to do with
hey this data center that they said
they're going to deliver with this much
capacity next year got delayed by 3
months that's not what cluster max
measures cluster max is explicitly
measuring sort of how how good is the
cluster for someone to use if you rent
the GPUs um how reliable is it? How
secure is it? How's the storage? How's
the network? How's the life cycle? How's
the slurm on Kubernetes? How are all
these things? Um in which case, you
know, it's just sort of I we try to be
more objective. Obviously, making a
rating pyramid is like, you know, it is
it is something you kind of have to do.
It would be nice if you could just make
a long report and no one cared if there
were no rankings. I mean, that's what
would happen. So, you kind of have to do
the rankings. Um and and set certain
boundaries and you can always litigate
the hell out of why and what is in what
tier. Um but like it is an objective
fact that we think Oracle is one of the
top Neoclouds in terms of quality of
service. Now that doesn't mean on the
other hand, hey at semi analysis in
April, we published to our clients that
their New Mexico data center was going
to be delayed because they weren't going
to get the uh pipelines. And this was a
big issue for OpenAI because OpenAI has
contracted a huge data center with them
in New Mexico. But if these pipelines
don't get built, this data center can't
go up. Um and then later you know we
said it again in uh May um and June and
then most recently Oracle announced a
force measure on it and their stock
tanked because of it right so so we're
disentangling two things right yes
Oracle is an amazing cloud at managed
for their managed cluster one of the top
Neoclouds but they also at the same time
may have execution issues whether it's
regulatory in the case of this New
Mexico data center where they can't get
the pipeline there or other issues you
know on their balance sheet right and so
that disentangling like what is good or
bad for the stock versus what are we
trying to test here. The goal in first
cluster max was
>> create something that people renting
GPUs can use. Um and it turns out now
like there's a lot of other uses for it
that people try to hamfist in whether
it's like you know um hey we're going to
write debt for this NeoCloud. If they're
new if they if they upgrade rankings
from bronze to silver their rate will
actually go down. Um you know things
like this or like hey I'm going to
invest in stocks that are at the top of
cluster max. Um so obvious these are not
the decision these are not what cluster
max is designed for. Um it's a data
point that you should use if you're
doing anything with these companies. But
um as far as Oracle as a company um
there's sort of like you know two things
to go here, right? Like one is they
signed a ton of AI data center deals um
with OpenAI. Um was it last year? Yeah,
it was last year. Holy crap, it was only
last year. Feels like eons ago. Um I
think it might have been exactly a year
ago. Um but the interesting thing is
they signed these massive deals. Um and
there's a number of issu risks embedded
with them. One is they signed them with
a fixed margin essentially. Um so now
that the price of GPUs has gone up a lot
for clouds, they can't take advantage of
this higher margin. So they're kind of
hammed in [clears throat] there. Number
two, um they raised a bunch of debt and
then the market started getting freaked
out about how much debt companies can
have and so they spooked out even though
Oracle is completely solvent. And then
number three, they have some execution
issues. You know, I mentioned the
regulatory one. There's some other data
centers that have some delays and such
there as well, but the main one being
this, you know, such as in in Wisconsin,
but the main one being this New Mexico
site that is delayed potentially
multiple years because of this pipeline
issue. Um, and so, you know, these
things can have very negative impacts on
the stock, but I think the company is
still fine. Now, you know, they're not
Nebius. Nebus gets to turn around and
they had the they have the shortest
average contract length of the top
clouds in cluster max. Um, and so Nebius
has been able to turn around and really
jack up pricing and take advantage of
this, right? Whereas coreweave and
Oracle despite having also good cluster
um you know management and clust and
reliability and security and all this
stuff were not able to take as much
advantage because they lock themselves
into long-term contracts primarily.
>> Oh that is fascinating. All right Jordan
let me ask you a technology question
then. um
you know as Dylan put out uh put out
there it is a pyramid um and there's
like these top tier uh groups like we
talked about coreweave and nebius Oracle
Google cloud is up there but in the
notrecommended section there's a lot of
logos uh there's underperforming and
unavailable
um I think there's more something like
more logos in the unavailable than you
know top four tiers combined
What do you think that says about the
fact that I mean, what do you think that
says about this technology that there's
so many that are out there uh that just
aren't meeting the bar for you?
>> Look, as people who are trying to
represent the interests of buyers, I
think it just makes us sad. It's sad to
see the uh
>> look it's sad to see that like a a year
and a half almost you know since um the
first version of cluster max was
published actually approaching 2 years
now um and since we coined the term
neocloud at semi analysis that a lot of
people have just not made progress
towards the things that we were writing
about and the things we were writing
about is just exactly what we talk to
the customers of these neoclouds about
what they
Um, and so I think it's just like the
dynamic of it being a sellers market
means that the priority for these
companies is how can they raise as much
money as they can, how can they build
data centers as fast as they can, and
how can they deploy chips as fast as
they can rather than working on the true
quality of the underlying service. And
that's that's a little bit of the
dynamic that you see represented there
where people can have these great
businesses without actually worrying too
much about delivering a great service
that their customers really enjoy and
recommend to other people. The other
thing is that I think there's like this
constant dynamic that we'll continue to
see over time which is that there can
only be so many leaders because there's
only so many people who truly innovate
and then everybody else copies them. And
when you have a market that by our
tracking is actually 323 providers as of
this morning uh which we track in our AI
cloud TCO model for people who are
subscribers to semi analysis they have
this full list. there's only a certain
amount of them that are even relevant,
like large enough to put on the list and
then a certain number of those that can
pass the bar for what we believe is what
we need to see to to recommend them. And
you know, in some ways, we think that
the bar for being recommended is quite
low. like the um the basic things that
fail with respect to security and
reliability being the two top ones are
just um
in our view dead simple and it's it's
just sad to see that others aren't
paying attention enough or caring enough
to actually implement this stuff.
>> Okay, two quick ones before we go. Um
just more broad question. Uh you know
Google obviously they're they've
announced they have this Gemini uh Argon
coming out. Gemini for Argon. Um, is it
your view that that you know there have
been some people who have called upon
Google to just be, you know, an
basically a NeoCloud and rent out uh the
TPUs from Google Cloud and the
computing. Um, do you see them going
that way or do you think that they're
still going to use like a large
percentage of their compute for model
training and inference? I mean
definitionally they have allocated less
compute to uh model training and
deployment um in the last 6 months than
they had two or three years ago. Um and
that that percentage allocation has
fallen over time. Um this is sort of you
know one of the things that we made a
joke about like uh maybe not even joke
but just a statement that Thomas Curran
won and Dennis lost right? Um now I
guess Karai um Google is producing
significantly more compute. um you know,
year on year, but the amount that's
going to deep mind is not rising as fast
on a you know, it's not like it's not
like oh Deep Mind had a third of
Google's compute, now it still has a
third of Google's compute. Um it's
actually falling as a percentage. Uh
which is really interesting because now
if I look at just DeepMind versus
Anthropic and OpenAI, DeepMind has the
least compute of the three um
by the end of this year. So like it's
it's a really it's really a big deal.
Um, and so Google, you know, whether or
not there's a Neil cloud, what the word
Neocloud even means, uh, you know, does
selling tokens of other models count as
Neocloud? Um, you know, does does, you
know, in a sense that's what the new
cloud business is, is selling AI model
tokens, right? So maybe that's a
neocloud, right? Um, the definition is
>> Blackstone and going and doing new
construction projects to build your GPUs
to deploy directly for customers outside
of your core platform
>> or selling chips, right? Is that
neocloud? No. I mean, they're selling a
lot of chips to anthropic. So it's, you
know, physically selling the chips
rather than like just renting them out.
So I would say like Google's business
model is evolving and they want to make
money at every layer of the stack. Um,
but by definition, you know, helping
Enthropic this much with TPUs, um, and
helping them this much with these other
things is hurting Google Deep Mind's
business. Um, okay.
>> I think they need they need to find a
niche, man. Like for Gemini, I mean,
nobody wants the third or fourth or
fifth best coding model. So they need to
find a niche that drives Gemini token
sales if they want Deep Mind to continue
competing on the frontier of AI research
and because right now it's I mean even
with this Gemini 4 argon release it's
just not there on coding compared to the
top two or three
>> and and and the risk here is what
happens next year when Open Entropic
both attempt to add 5 to 10 gawatt of
additional compute for their labs and
you know for open eye andropic each and
then Um, Google only adds a few
gigawatts. Now their compute deficit, it
it was Google was way ahead in compute
and they were kind of behind slash
equivalent. Um, mostly just a little bit
behind. Um, and now they've fallen
further behind, but their compute is the
same. So what happens when they have
less compute? Are they do they somehow
magically catch up? It's possible,
right? They have the talent, they have
the people, they need to reorganize and
really focus up. Um but also like more
and more of the best people just keep
getting poached to anthropic to open AI
and it it's it meta
>> discovery loop.
>> Yeah.
>> Discovery loop.
>> Discovery loop. Right.
>> Okay. I I want to ask one more before we
go if that's okay. Um you know the I
think Dylan you've said in the past that
um the the people who are getting most
of the value out of the AI models that
are created are the end users, right?
The people that are using the clouds for
instance at the you know at the base.
Um, and of course, Anthropic makes that
model available via API and to go into
all these various uses. You know, it's
it's going to have to do more licensing
and and who knows if they'll be able to
do products for all this. I'm curious if
you think if you see a scenario where
given the big numbers that we talked
about in the past um or they keep their
frontier models at home for longer, much
longer, and use them to build their own
products. It's like we know they have
the wet lab, we know they have cloud
code uh and co-work um and then they
don't make them available because they
want to get more margin out of the
infrastructure that they've they've
bought and built.
>> Yeah. So, I mean I think I think we've
already seen this, right? Um Anthropic
had Mythos ready in February. Uh they've
their model safety cards not noted uh
noted that they have two other models
since Methos that have released and
publicly we still don't have full
Methos. We have a neutered version of it
called Fable. Um, and it it took many
many months before Fable even came out.
They had the glass wing which was like
mythos but for only some subsectors and
it was neutered in some areas, right?
Not all areas. And so it's clear that
Anthropic has not released new models.
Open eye. Likewise, Astra was actually
done a couple months ago and it only
came out like, you know, it took a
couple months before they released
Astra. Um and the new model bell um they
even showed a blog where they showed the
performance of it in math um and how it
you know solved all this stuff um and
they have not released it. So clearly
they are just using it internally not
externally and and so you know the labs
have already moved along this line right
where it's like oh yeah yeah the gap
between them and and Chinese open source
is still 6 months um they're kind of
keeping that but in reality they've kept
you know months of progress internal
only um because the moment you make it
external people can distill it um you
know and all these other things so I
think you know enthropic will likely
release a new model in the coming weeks
you know for their IPO Um I think open I
will likely have to release a new model
in the coming weeks as well just because
it's such a competitive environment but
at the same time they are like keeping a
lot of their stuff internal only.
Yeah, we were discussing internally some
of the uh capitalistic incentives. If if
the incentives are actually going to
motivate people to release more models
and get them in the hands of consumers
because of the incredible gross margins
on the per token API pricing or if the
incentive is to keep it internally so
that you can pursue the end user
applications which are even more uh high
value than selling the access to the
model per token. It's going to be
interesting to see how it plays out. But
in one of those scenarios,
the capitalist approach will be to pace
the frontier for yourself, right?
>> And which what's your gut on where it's
going to go? Which one of those
scenarios you think plays out?
>> I think Anthropic has publicly stated
that they are pacing the frontier by
keeping themselves
uh restricted. And that's the only way
that their blog posts have manifest in
reality. Nobody else is slowing down.
They're only slowing themselves down. I
think that's true. I think that's what's
happening. And uh I think the incentives
to both improve the status of AI by
solving things that are, you know, like
cancer that are just unequivocally good
that everybody can agree is a good thing
would be, you know, a positive
incentive. And then I think there's also
plenty of money to be made if you do
something like that. So I my my bet is
that we continue to see the minimum
viable models released by both openai
and anthropic to keep a lead over
Chinese and the rest of the open source
ecosystem. The website semianalysis.com
uh sign up for the blog as Dylan says,
you know, sign up for the newsletter as
I have. Uh it's a wealth of insight and
analysis and I think you'll love it if
you're not there already. Uh and this
conversation has just, you know, been
the manifestation of that. So, uh,
Dylan, great to see you again. Jordan,
really nice to meet you. You guys are
welcome anytime, and we appreciate your
time today.
>> Thanks for having us, Alex.
>> Thanks, Alex.
>> All right, good stuff. Thanks everybody
for listening and watching, and we'll
see you next time on Big Technology
Podcast.